Register to The Leo Ornstein Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Leo Ornstein Papers
1892-1989
MSS 10
Yale University Music Library
32
(25 boxes)
Music, photographs, and additional materials by and about the Russian-American composer Leo Ornstein (ca. 1893-2002)
Ornstein, Leo, 1892-2002
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Leo Ornstein Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Leo Ornstein in 1973.
Arrangement
In 3 series as follows: I. Music. II. Photographs. III. Miscellaneous.
Scope and Contents
The Leo Ornstein Papers contain sketches, manuscript scores, and published editions of Ornstein's musical compositions, including songs, piano pieces, chamber music, and orchestral works. The majority of the manuscripts are in the hand of Ornstein's wife, Pauline. The Papers also hold photographs, programs and reviews, biographical clippings, and prose writings by Pauline Ornstein.
The Leo Ornstein Papers also include materials that have not yet been processed. Please consult the Special Collections staff for further information.
Biographical / Historical
Initially regarded as a child prodigy and enfant terrible, Leo Ornstein outlasted his admirers and critics alike; born in the nineteenth century, he lived into the twenty-first. His compositional career may well be the longest in music history; stretching over eight decades, it surpasses those of even such famously long-lived composers as Verdi, Stravinsky, and Havergal Brian.
Leo Ornstein was born in the Ukrainian city of Kremenchug in 1892 or 1893. (The exact date has not been firmly established.) The son of a rabbi, he began his musical studies at home. At the age of ten he entered the conservatory of St. Petersburg, where he studied with Anna Esipova and Alexander Glazunov. After the failed Russian revolution of 1905, the Ornstein family fled to the United States, settling on the Lower East Side of Manhattan. Ornstein continued his musical education at the Institute of Musical Art (later known as the Juilliard School), studying piano with Bertha Tapper and harmony with Percy Goetschius. He made his New York debut in 1911 and was immediately hailed as a supremely gifted pianist.
Ornstein soon made his mark as a composer as well. Works such as Wild Men's Dance and Suicide in an Airplane aroused critical controversy as a result of Ornstein's new compositional vocabulary, which included startling dissonances, percussive sonorities, and driving rhythms. Critics sometimes grouped him with Schoenberg and Stravinsky as leaders of the modernist movement. Ornstein's reputation was not limited to the United States; in 1913-14, he undertook a European concert tour. He created a sensation in Berlin, Paris, and London, and he became friends with leading musicians and critics, such as Ferruccio Busoni and M.D. Calvocoressi. After returning home Ornstein continued to perform regularly, and he was widely regarded as one of the most important young musicians in America. Frederick H. Martins published a short biography in 1918, Leo Ornstein: The Man, His Ideas, His Work.
In 1918 Ornstein married Pauline Mallet-Prévost, who had also been a piano student of Bertha Tapper. They had two children. Ornstein usually composed by dictating the music to his wife, so most of the manuscripts in the Ornstein Papers are in her hand.
Despite his extraordinary pianistic talents, Ornstein did not enjoy the stress, travel, and social obligations of life as a touring virtuoso. He began to curtail his concert schedule in the early 1920s, and by the early '30s, he had withdrawn from the concert stage altogether. Instead, he turned to pedagogy; for several years he was a member of the faculty at the Philadelphia Musical Academy. He later established the Ornstein School of Music in Philadelphia, where he taught until his retirement in the mid-1950s. He and his wife later settled in Brownsville, Texas and then in Green Bay, Wisconsin. He died in Green Bay on February 24, 2002.
After Ornstein stopped performing in public, his music also faded from view. Although he continued to compose prolifically, he came to favor a less radical style than the one that had brought him into the limelight. Meanwhile, a new generation of modernist composers came to the fore, and by the 1950s, Ornstein was largely forgotten. Towards the end of the twentieth century, there were signs of an Ornstein revival, however. His son Severo Ornstein published many of his works under imprint of the Poon Hill Press, and several have been recorded. Historians now recognize Ornstein as a pivotal figure in the early history of musical modernism.
Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Piano music; Songs; String quartets -- Scores; Ornstein, Leo, 1892-2002; Ornstein, Pauline
- Music, Series I
  General
  Ornstein's musical works have been divided into four categories according to genre:
  A. Vocal Works, arranged alphabetically
  B. Piano Works: Solo piano works, arranged alphabetically; Solo piano sonatas, untitled works, unfinished works; Music for more than one performer
  C. Chamber Music: With winds and one other instrument; With strings and one other instrument; Ensembles
  D. Orchestral Music
  - Vocal Works, I.A
    Arranged alphabetically
    - America, 3 p. each (Box 1, Folder 1)
      C. Fischer publications
      SA (2 copies); SSA (1 copy); SAB (1 copy); SATB (1 copy); TTBB (1 copy)
    - The corpse, voice & piano (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Holograph score in ink [written before 1918] -- 13 p.
      New Music publication, April, 1928 -- 15 p.
    - Cradle song for voice, piano & violin ad lib., op. 33, no. 1, 9 p. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      C. Fischer publication, c1915
      [op. 33, nos. 2 & 3 were also published, but are not in the collection: no. 2 - A vision of glory; no. 3 - Alone in the forest (with violin part)]
    - Lullaby, 6 p. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      purple copy
    - Mother o' mine (words by Kipling), 5 p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      C. Fischer publication, c1916
    - Tartar lament (words by Frederick Martens), 7 p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      C. Fischer publication, c1918
      [this is no. 2 of Two Oriental songs. No. 1 is not in the collection]
    - There was a jolly miller once, 5 p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Three Russian Choruses, op. 61. SATB a cappella (Box 1, Folder 2)
      (piano part for rehearsal)
      - No. 1 - Russian Lament, 9 p.
        Associated Music publication, c1928
        Photocopy of same
      - No. 2 - Russian Winter, 11 p.
        Associated Music publication, c1918
      - No. 3 - Russian Festival, 13 p.
        Breitkopf & Härtel publication, c1918
    - 5 songs op. 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      (later arranged for voice and orchestra)
      no titles: mimeographs of first 4, photocopy of 5th from the holographs
      - Dawn beyond windows..., 1927; 8 p.
      - Streets of stone unending..., 1928 July; 8 p.
      - Life burns bright and I am alone..., 1927; 10 p.
      - Sing! The sun, the earth is song..., no date; 13 p.
      - Shades of tremulous color garment the single hued sunlight..., 1927 Aug. 17; 7 p.
    - 4 songs without words (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - no. 1, 6 p.
        mimeograph or purple ink of holograph score
        2 copies
      - no. 2, 1928 July 28; 7 p.
      - no. 3, 1928 June 16-18; 9 p.
        holograph score in ink
      - no. 4, 9 p.
        holograph score in pencil
  - Piano Works, I.B
    - A la chinoise, op. 39, 29 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Breitkopf & Härtel publications, c1918
    - Arabesques, op. 42, no. 1-9, 13 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Publisher's proof, c1920
    - Arabesques for the pianoforte, op. 42, 19 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Breitkopf & Härtel, Inc., c1921
      (Photocopy)
      Contains 3 unnumbered pages at end with first pages of A la Chinoise, op. 39; A la Mexicana, op. 35, no. 2; and Scherzino, op. 5, no. 2
    - Arabesques, op. 42, 19 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      With Ornstein's pencil markings, 1976
    - At twilight, op. 10, 22 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      A. P. Schmidt, c1911
      [2 copies]
      [Photocopy of Copyist's manuscript]
      Romance triste
      Coquedry [i.e., Coquetry]
      Nocturne
      In modo Scarlatti
      Souvenir mélancolique (In remembrance)
      Capricietto
    - An autumn improvisation, 15 November 1978; 16 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Copyist's manuscript signed
    - An autumnal fantasy, 13 October 1978; 10 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bagatelle, no. 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Holograph in pencil -- 3 p.
      Holograph in ink -- 3 p.
    - Ballade, 21 December 1976; 19 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Barbaro: a pantomime, 30 November 1978; 17 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Originally "Vignette J"
    - Barcarolle, op. 6, no. 4, 4 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Holograph in ink, markings in red
    - Burlesca (a satire), 23 September 1976; 20 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      (Dedicated to William Westney)
      Joshua Corp. Ed.
    - Cossack Impressions, op. 14, 15, 17 p. (Box 2, Folder 1a)
      W. Hansen publication (2 vols.), c1914
      Book 1:
      Evening Song - Abendlied
      Maidens at the Fountain - Mädchen an der Quelle
      Mazurka
      Moonlight in the Mountains - Mondschein in dem Bergen
      Grief - Sorge
      The Waltz - Der Walzer
      The Nocturne - Nocturne
      Book 2:
      At Dawn - Morgendämmerung
      The dance - Der Tanz
      The love song - Liebesgesang
      The march - Marsch
      Méditation
      At the festival - Zum Fest
    - A dream almost forgotten, 24 February 1977; 22 p. (Box 2, Folder 1a)
    - Dwarf Suite (Suite de gnomes), op. 11, 43 p. (Box 2, Folder 1a)
      Schott publication, c1915
      Dwarfs at dawn
      Dance of the dwarfs
      Funeral march of the gnomes
      Serenade of the dwarfs
      Dwarfs at work
      Marche grotesque
    - Fantasy pieces, Four, 6, 7, 6 p. (Box 2, Folder 1a)
      Nos. 1, 3, & 4 in pencil holograph
    - Five piano pieces, July 1978; 29 p. (Box 2, Folder 1a)
    - Impressions de la Tamise, op. 13, no. 1, 14 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Schott publication, c1920
    - Impressions de Notre-Dame, Two, op. 16, no. 1-2, 16 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Schott publication, c1914 [photocopy]
    - Impromptu, 28 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      At the grave of an infant (has title: Epitaph) (3 October 1976)
      An interlude (27 October 1976)
      A bit of Nostalgia (11 November 1976)
    - In the country, cycle for piano, 11 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      G. Schirmer publication, c1924
      The gypsy lament
      The old dungeon
      A fairy dance
      The cathedral bells and the choir
      The merry-go-round
    - Intermezzo IA, 8 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Holograph in ink
    - Intermezzo IIA, 7 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Intermezzo IIE, August 1968; 7 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Copy of copyist's manuscript signed
    - Intermezzo IIE, 25 August 1968; 8 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Intermezzo III, 20 March 1968; 7 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Copy of holograph
    - Intermezzo IV, 5 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Intermezzo V, 30 October 1968; 9 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Just a fun piece, 29 June 1978; 15 p. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Memories from childhood, a cycle for piano, 17 p. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      G. Schirmer publication, c1925
      A tale from the moon
      The organgrinder and the monkey
      In grandpapa's big rocker
      The funny story
      An Arabian fable
      In the swing
      The sleeping doll
      March of the tin soldiers
    - Mindy's piece, 1967 Jan 14; 41, 4 p. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Holograph in ink, signed
      Holograph in pencil
      Written for granddaughter when child
    - A morning in the woods, 29 September 1971; 11 p. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      [one reel microfilm]
    - A morning in the woods, 29 September 1971; 11 p. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Copy of copyist's manuscript signed with addition of pencil corrections
    - Musings of a piano, 9 p. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      The professor walks by
      The piano thinks out loud
      The music lesson and the complaining child
      I wish I knew
    - Nocturne No. 1, written ca. 1922; 20 p. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Nocturne No. II, 36 p. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Holograph in ink, markings in red (his hand)
    - Poems of 1917, op. 41, 54 p. (Box 2a, Folder 4)
      Carl Fischer publication, c1918
      No man's land
      The sower of despair
      The orient in Flanders
      The wrath of the despoiled
      Night brooding over the battlefield
      A dirge of the trenches
      Song behind the lines
      The battle
      The army at prayer
      Dance of the dead
    - Piano pieces, op. 17, no. 1-5 (Box 2a, Folder 4)
      Holograph in pencil, with red markings (his hand)
      Volga (Song of the Bayemen)
      Natasha (Smiles and coquetry)
      Potok (Dirge of the Merijicks)
      Mirig i Jinka (The old couple dance)
      Doumka (Grief in the heart)
    - Piano sketch book, 40, 39 p. (Box 2a, Folder 4)
      Elkan-Vogel publication, c1939 - 2 vols.
    - 3 preludes, op. 20, 11 p. (Box 2a, Folder 4)
      B. Schott's Söhne, c1914 [photocopy]
    - The recruit and the bugler, 24 August 1978; 11 p. (Box 2a, Folder 4)
    - Seeing Russia with teacher (ten descriptive duets) (Box 2a, Folder 5)
      G. Schirmer publication, c1925 - 2 vols.
      Book 1 -- 11 p.
      The old village church
      Putting the wooden doll to sleep
      The sleigh ride
      The prisoners leave for Siberia
      The Carrousel
      Book 2 -- 11 p.
      The Moujik in the dark woods
      Baba tells an old tale
      The Cossacks ride by
      The barge on the Dnieper
      Holiday in the village
    - Serenade for the pianoforte, op. 5, no. 1, 6 p. (Box 2a, Folder 5)
      Breitkopf Pulications, Inc., c1918
      1 original and [photocopy]
      [Last page contains page 1 of op. 5, no. 2 - Scherzino]
    - Six water colors for piano, op. 80, 21 p. (Box 2a, Folder 5)
      Carl Fischer, c1921
      (2 copies)
    - A small Carnival, 21 July 1978; 10 p. (Box 2a, Folder 5)
    - Solitude, 5 August 1978; 9 p. (Box 2a, Folder 5)
      [Formerly titled "Departure": see letter 10/78]
    - Some New York Scenes, 11 March 1971; 20 p. (Box 2a, Folder 5)
      Holograph in black ink, markings in blue ink
    - Suicide in an airplane, 16 p. (Box 2a, Folder 5)
      Holograph in black ink (his hand)
    - Suite russe, op. 12, 16 p. (Box 2a, Folder 5)
      W. Hansen publication, c1914
      Doumka
      Extase
      Barcarole
      Mélancolie
      Danse Burlesque
      Berceuse
      Chanson pathétique
    - Tarantelle, 11 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
      Photocopy of Holograph
      1 reel of microfilm
    - Tarantelle diabolique, 29 July 1960; 16 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
    - Three landscapes, date is cut off of photocopy; 13 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
      Evening's sorrow
      Copy of Copyist's manuscript signed
      [is possibly intended to be part of Morning in the Woods or Some New York Scenes]
    - Three landscapes, October 1968; 13 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
      Evening's sorrow (revised version)
    - Three moods: Anger-Grief-Joy, 34 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
      2 copies of holograph
      1 reel of negative film
    - Three Tales, 57 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
      A rendez-vous at the lake (30 June 1977)
      A fantasy (29 July 1977)
      A Midnight Waltz (9 June 1977)
    - To a Grecian Urn, 4 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
    - Two lyric pieces - II. Waltz, 9 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
      Carl Fischer, Inc., c1924 [photocopy]
    - Valse diabolique, 22 January 1977; 26 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
    - Vignettes for piano, 85 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
      A (12 September 1977)
      B (21 September 1977)
      C (9 October 1977)
      D (29 September 1977)
      E (23 October 1977)
      F (17 November 1977). Also includes pencil copy. 11 p. [n.d.]
      G (11 November 1977)
      H (2 December 1977)
      I (no date no signature)
    - Wild men's dance (Danse sauvage), op. 13, no. 2, 21 p. (Box 2a, Folder 6)
      3 copies
    - Other Piano Works
      - Fourth piano sonata, 45 p. (Box 3, Folder 1)
        Photocopy of printed copy
      - Biography in sonata form, 116 p. (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
        I. Vigor-Passion
        II. Youth's Melancholy
        III. Some flashbacks - Spring on the banks of the Dnieper - Forebodings of childhood's end: Last moments in the swing - Early sorrows - Far away and long ago - The agony and ecstasy of approaching manhood
        IV. Epilogue
      - 15 Waltzes (written mostly between 1950-1972) (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
        Holograph scores, mostly in pencil
      - Compositions numbered 1-42 (no titles; written 1950-1972) (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
        Holograph scores
      - Four untitled pieces (Box 3, Folder 9a)
        [F?] (July 1967) -- 12 p.
        "G" (May 1963) -- 4 p.
        "H" (28 November 1966) -- 5 p.
        "I" (1965) -- 5 p.
        copy of copyist's manuscripts signed
      - Unfinished piano piece, 9 p. (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Nocturne [childhood effort of Leo's] op. 113, no. 2, 6 p. (Box 3, Folder 10)
        Holograph in ink (his hand)
        Child's scribble and sketches of music at end
      - Two improvisations, op. 95 (4 hands), 26 p. (Box 3a, Folder 1)
        No. 1 - [wanting]
        No. 2 - Valse Buffon
        Holograph in ink (his hand, 1921)
      - Piece four piano (4 hands), op. 19, no. 1, 1913; 10 p. (Box 3a, Folder 2)
        Part in ink holograph
      - Sonata for 2 pianos, op. 89, 168 p. (Box 3a, Folder 3)
        [includes pencil sketches at end of 2nd. movement]
      - Prelude tragique (for piano four hands), 15 p. (Box 3a, Folder 4)
      - Scherzino, op. 5, no. 2, 5 p. (Box 3a, Folder 5)
        Breitkopf & Härtel, 1918
      - Moment Musical, Schubert-Ornstein, op. 51, no. 1, 4 p. (Box 3a, Folder 6)
        [last page contains page 1 of Scherzino, op. 5, no.23]
      - A set of seven Waltzes (Box 3a, Folder 7)
        Number [?] July 6th, 1979 -- 9 p.
        Number III June 3, 1979 -- 7 p.
        Number IV June 19th, 1979 -- 11 p.
        Number IV? June 29, 1974 -- 14 p.
      - Miscellaneous Waltzes (Box 3a, Folder 8)
        [given the following numberings at Mrs. Ornstein's request]
        Waltz No. 7 January 11th 1980 -- 7 p.
        Waltz No. 8 April 16th 1980 -- 7 p.
        Waltz No. 9 February 8th 1980 -- 14 p.
        Waltz No. 14 May 17th 1980 -- 17 p.
      - A la Mexicana (three pieces in folk-style for the pianoforte) op. 35, 12 p. (Box 3a, Folder 9)
        Breitkopf & Härtel, Inc. New York c1920 (photocopy)
      - A Chromatic Dance, December 29th 1978; 15 p. (Box 3a, Folder 9)
      - A Chromatic Dance, 13 p. (Box 3a, Folder 9)
        General Music Publishing, c1980
      - A Reverie, April 21, 1979; 7 p. (Box 3a, Folder 9)
  - Chamber Music, I.C
    - With wind instruments, I.C.1
      - Minuet in ancient style for flute & clarinet, 4 p. (Box 4, Folder 1)
        Holograph score in ink
        Offset copies of 2 parts - slurs in blue ink (2 p. each)
      - Prelude in ancient [antique] style for flute & clarinet (Box 4, Folder 1)
        Offset master of score -- 7 p.
        Offset copy of score
        Holograph set of 2 parts -- 4 p. each
        Photocopy of flute part
      - Allegro for flute & piano [called Intermezzo], 1959 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        Holograph score in pencil -- 19 p.
        Holograph flute part in ink -- 5 p.
        Photocopy of holograph flute part
        Photocopy of alternate B-flat clarinet part -- 5 p.
        Photocopy of alternate B-flat clarinet part -- 4 p.
        Allegro for flute and piano (Feb. 20th, 1979) -- 17 p.
        Prelude for flute & piano -- 13 p.
      - Nocturne for clarinet & piano, 17 p. (Box 4, Folder 3)
        Holograph part in ink for clarinet
      - Ballade for Clarinet in B-flat, 2 p. (Box 4, Folder 3a)
        Photocopy of Copyist's manuscript
      - Ballade for sax & piano (Box 4, Folder 4)
        Holograph score in ink -- 11 p.
        Photocopy of holograph alternate B-flat clarinet part -- 2 p.
        Holograph sax part in ink
        Holograph alternate viola part in ink
        New set with corrections (see enclosed correspondence)
    - With stringed instruments, I.C.2
      - Hebraic Fantasy, violin & piano, 13 p. (Box 4, Folder 5)
        Offset copy of holograph score
        Photocopy of holograph violin part
      - Waltz, violin & piano, 8 p. (Box 4, Folder 5)
        Holograph score in pencil
      - Violin sonata (manuscript; not op. 31), 42 p. (Box 4, Folder 6)
        Holograph score in ink of slow movement only
      - Sonata for violin and piano, op. 31, 43 p. (Box 4, Folder 6)
        Carl Fischer, 1915
        Includes violin part (11 p.)
        Photocopy
      - Violin sonata, op. 26, 23 p. (Box 4, Folder 7)
        Publisher's proof of score and part (22 May 1918)
        Pencil corrections added throughout
      - Fantasy pieces for viola & piano (Box 4, Folder 8)
        I Score: 1 manuscript, 2 photocopies (17 p.); copyist's score (13 p.) -- Nov. 1980.
        II Never written
        III Holograph score (23 October 1972) -- 19 p.
        Photocopy of holograph score
        Holograph part
        Photocopy of holograph part
        Photocopy of copyist's manuscript signed
      - Six Preludes for violoncello & piano, 55 p. (Box 4, Folder 9)
        Holograph score
        Mimiographed part from the holograph, with corrections -- 19 p.
        One reel of negative microfilm
      - Violoncello sonata, op. 52, 72 p. (Box 4, Folder 10)
        C. Fischer publication
      - Violoncello sonata, no. 2, ca. 1920 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        Holograph score in black-ink - stems etc... in blue ink -- 49 p.
        Photocopy of holograph part -- 8 p.
      - Composition no. 36 for cello and piano, 8 p. (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - [Untitled], op. 33, no. 1 & 2, for violoncello & piano, 4 p. (Box 4, Folder 11)
        Holograph score in ink - slurs in red ink
    - Music for Chamber ensemble, I.C.3
      - String quartet, op. 28, 61 p. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - String quartet, op. 99 [full score], 53 p. (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Copy of copyist's manuscript signed with US copyright indication
      - String quartet, op. 99 [last movement only], 19 p. (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Holograph set of parts in ink
      - String quartet No. III, 1976; 114 p. (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
        Copyist's manuscript of parts [individually foliated for each movement]
        1st. violin (21 p.); 2nd. violin (17 p.); viola (21 p.); violoncello (15 p.)
      - Quintet for piano & strings, 269 p. (Box 5a, Folder 1-2)
        Offset copy of score (white on black); with ink on white paper taped in corrections
      - Quintet for piano & strings, 28 p. each (Box 5a, Folder 3)
        Photocopy set of holograph parts
        One reel each of positive & negative mircrofilm
      - Quintette, for piano & strings, op. 92, 1929; 271 p. (Box 5a, Folder 4)
        [full score]
        [Photocopies of the LC manuscript with two corrections added by Mrs. Ornstein]
      - Quintette, for piano & strings, op. 92, 1929; 107 p. (Box 5a, Folder 4)
        String parts
  - Orchestral Music, I.D
    - Nocturne, 76 p. (Box 6)
      Holograph set of parts in ink:
      34 wind, 10 violin I, 10 violin II, 8 viola, 8 violoncello, 6 bass
    - Dance of the Fates, 52 p. (Box 7)
      Holograph set of parts in ink: 35 wind, 10 violin I, 10 violin II, 8 viola, 7 violoncello, 7 bass
    - Five Songs for voice & orchestra (Texts by Waldo Frank) (Box 8)
      Song I: Holograph score in ink, with text underlay in pencil (18 p.)
      Holograph set of parts:
      8 wind, 8 violin I, 7 violin II, 9 viola, 8 cello, 6 bass